A Guide to the Additional Records of the Virginia Society of Ornithology, 1932-2004
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Additional Records of the Virginia Society of Ornithology 1932-2004
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12632-c
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection is a gift from the Virginia Society of Ornithology, through Gene Sattler, to the University of Virginia Library on May 26, 2005.
Biographical/Historical Information
The organization was founded in 1929 and exists to encourage the systematic study of birds in Virginia, to stimulate interest in birds, and to assist the conservation of wildlife and other natural resources. Activities undertaken by the Society include an annual meeting held in a different part of the state each year, featuring talks on ornithological subjects and field trips to nearby areas; other field trips lasting a day or more and scheduled throughout the year so as to include all seasons and to cover the major physiographic regions of the state; publication of the journal The Raven, a newsletter, and Virginia Birds; study projects such as nesting studies and winter bird population surveys. In addition, local chapters of the Society, located in some of the larger cities and towns of Virginia, conduct their own programs of meetings, field trips, and other projects.
Scope and Content
The Additional Records of the Virginia Society of Ornithology, 1932-2004, include correspondence of Bill Williams, the President, and John Bazuin, the Vice President; board meeting minutes and treasurer's reports; bird reports; bird sightings at Wallops Island by Charles Vaughn; a birding log by Norwood Middleton "Woody;" a Christmas Bird Count at Chincoteague, Virginia; a guide of Where to Bird in Virginia; membership lists; and research by Joshua F. B. Camblos, M.D. from 1930 to 1939. Correspondents include Senator Paul S. Trible, Jr. and Senator John Warner. There are ca.1200 items in 4 hollinger boxes, (1.25 linear feet).
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by topic and chronologically within each folder.
Contents List
- Annotated Bibliography of Virginia Ornithology, 1989, 1 item. (Box-folder 1:1)
- Bird Records part one, 1993-1999, 63 items. (Box-folder 1:2)
- Bird Records part two, 1993-1999, 54 items. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Bird Records, 1999-2002, 59 items. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Bird Sightings: Wallops Island by Charles Vaughn, [1970-1993], 57 items. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Birding log part one by Norwood Middleton Woody, 1974-1980, 2 items. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Birding log part two by Norwood Middleton Woody, 1981-1987, 2 items. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Birding log part three by Norwood Middleton Woody, 1988-1989, 2 items. (Box-folder 1:8)
- Birding log part four by Norwood Middleton Woody, 1990-1993, 1 item. (Box-folder 1:9)
- Birding log part five by Norwood Middleton Woody, 1990-1997, 1 item. (Box-folder 1:10)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1974-1989, 29 items. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1990-2004, 50 items. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Christmas Bird Count-Chincoteague, 1990, 13 items. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Correspondence-Banding, 1956-1981, 50 items. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Correspondence-Bird Records, 1949-1954, 56 items. (Box-folder 2:5)
- Correspondence-Bird Records, 1955-1957, 13 items. (Box-folder 3:1)
- Correspondence-Bird Records, 1960-1985, 30 items. (Box-folder 3:2)
- Correspondence-John Bazuin, 1988-1989, 61 items. (Box-folder 3:3)
- Correspondence-Frederic R. Scott, 1969-1970, 2 items. (Box-folder 3:4)
- Correspondence-Bill Williams, 1987, 64 items. (Box-folder 3:5)
- Correspondence-Bill Williams, 1988, 101 items. (Box-folder 3:6)
- Correspondence-Bill Williams, 1989-1991, 55 items. (Box-folder 3:7)
- Correspondence-Bill Williams News clippings, 1987-1988, 22 items. (Box-folder 3:8)
- May Guide: Where to Bird in Virginia, 1981, 1 notebook. (Box-folder 4:1)
- Logo for the Society, n. d., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:2)
- Membership lists, 1977-2003, 10 items. (Box-folder 4:3)
- Membership Questionnaire, 1987-1988, 54 items. (Box-folder 4:4)
- Research on Egg Data by Joshua F. B. Camblos, M. D., 1932-1939, 1 item. (Box-folder 4:5)
- Treasurer's Report 2001-2004, 9 items. (Box-folder 4:6)